



Joben Gohlke

iOS Developer & Educator

Lambda School

iOS Program Manager 08/2019 - 06/2020

iOS Instructor 04/2019 - 06/2020

StackPath

Senior Application Developer 11/2017 - 03/2020

The Iron Yard

Mentor Instructor 06/2016 - 04/2017

Lead Instructor Curriculum Lead - iOS 05/2015 - 06/2016

Mobile Instructor 01/2015 - 11/2017

Current Experience

Responsible for managing 6 direct-report instructors on instructional excellence, professional development, and mentorship best practices. Also provided cross functional leadership to Admissions, Student Success, Marketing, Curriculum, and Assessment. Acted as a subject matter expert for the iOS curriculum.

Lead 11 cohorts of dozens of students at a time to learn the fundamentals of software development, mobile design, and iOS architecture in a virtual, live classroom setting. Made extensive contributions to curriculum refinement. Assisted in Admissions recruitment by partipating in webinars of prospective students.

Built VPN clients for iOS. Helped maintain a backend framework for iOS and Mac to interface with the Apple-provided NEVPNManager and associated classes to configure and manage personal VPN configurations. Built version 2 of StrongVPN to spec from designs provided by StackPath design team.

As Lead Instructor (and later a Mentor Instructor), provided counsel and training for newer instructors into the organization. Performed biweekly one-on-one meetings with each member of my instructor team and set the agenda for the biweekly group meetings. This was done remotely as TIY is a distributed company. Was also involved in certain HR functions for the aforementioned team members, things like: yearly performance reviews, disciplinary actions (those were rare), and new instructor onboarding. Provided subject matter expertise for the iOS curriculum. Maintained both the scope of what was to be taught as well as example lessons, assignments, and small projects for students. Advised and worked with fellow iOS instructors to advance the curriculum as Apple released updates to the OS and the two programming languages supported on the platform.

Taught 6 cohorts of Mobile Engineering on the Orlando campus. Responsible for all iOS curriculum, which included: lecture content and example applications, homework descriptions, resources, and finished projects. Performed 3 hour lectures 4 days-a-week for the first 9 weeks of the 12 week course. Provided mentorship to each student and was responsible for their academic advancement. Responsible for homework grading and academic record-keeping. During the final 3 weeks of each class, provided mentorship, counsel, and project management of each student or group final project, a capstone app that showcases the individual talents of each student.

Joben Gohlke

iOS Developer & Educator

iOS Orlando Meetup

Member since: 11/2012 Organizer/leader since: 1/2018

Organizations

Lead monthly meetings about iOS development topics for interested parties of all skill levels. Presented at meetings on topics spanning from introductory language demos to advanced level iOS concepts.

BlueToad, Inc.

Senior iOS Developer 04/2014 - 12/2014

Past Experience

Tasked with ownership and management of main iOS publication reader application. App was designed and architected for reading digital publications and other magazine style content (including retail store circulars, medical journals, etc) and has been deployed to over 1000 instances in the App Store. App was maintained by a team of three outsourced developers. Responsible for managing the task assignments of these developers as well as setting the scope and pace of development of new features. Architected a major UI and business logic overhaul of the existing application to prepare it for compatibility with iOS 7/8. Designed and developed a new Article Viewer interface for consuming content. It provided a more news-like reading environment for users to consume content from the magazine issue. This included building a data model for fetching and storing article content separate from the main app and creating a view hierarchy and interaction model for navigating between the article viewer and the page viewer of the pre-existing interface.

SecureNet Technologies

Senior iOS Developer 11/2013 - 03/2014 Worked with web designers and developers to adapt an existing web-based application for use as a native mobile app for iOS and Android platforms. App is used by independent security system dealer technicians while in the field performing alarm installations and maintenance at both residential and commercial sites.

Presidio

iOS Developer 02/2013 - 06/2013 (Contract) Worked with Presidio management to plan and design an iPad-based CRM for their account managers. Also designed, created and managed the enterprise wide launch of an iPhone-based receipt image tracking application for attaching to expense reports.

Joben Gohlke

iOS Developer & Educator

Transaction Data Systems

Lead iOS Developer 05/2010 - 02/2013

Software Engineer 01/2009 - 05/2010

Northrop Grumman

Software Engineer 04/2008 - 12/2008 (Internship)

Transaction Data Systems

Technical Support Analyst 07/2002 - 04/2008

University of Central Florida

2002 - 2008

Past Experience

Built an app to allow pharmacy patients to refill their prescriptions by scanning the prescription barcode. Oversaw the design and implementation of an Android variant of RefillRx Mobile by a third party company. Working with another iOS developer, designed and coded an iPad app for pharmacies to process their prescription deliveries.

Worked with C# and .NET Compact Framework to develop Windows Mobile applications. Also used Java to create a Windows backup solution for a PostgreSQL database and created many BASH shell scripts to perform regular maintenance of customers' Linux systems.

Responsible for a Java-based reporting tool used in support of the main product, a multi-theater, high level war-game simulator for JFCOM, the military's former department for inter-forces cooperation. Led a UI and backend rewrite of the reporting tool to increase its effectiveness.

Provided phone-based technical support for a user base of approximately 3000 independent pharmacies. Supported Redhat Linux and Windows-based computer systems and associated peripherals. Also responsible for several widely-used BASH shell scripts, including one that provided regular updates for the core product, Rx30.

Education

Coursework in Computer Science